235 Clayton Rd. Schenectady, NY 12304-3817 518-229-1182 resume@kc2idf.com

Summary

Over 20 years of IT experience in System Administration and DevOps Engineering. Passionate about learning new technologies. Friendly, hard working team player, looking for a team that values experience and collaboration. Able to telecommute.

Qualification Highlights

- Skilled System Administrator, experienced with Linux, JBoss, WebLogic, Tomcat, Apache, nginx, PostgreSQL, NetApp, Isilon, Hitachi and Dell/EMC SAN storage.
- Excellent verbal and written communication skills
- · Scientific approach to problem solving

Technical expertise

Operating Systems: Linux (Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL), CentOS, Ubuntu Server, Ubuntu desktop, Slackware, NetRunner, LinuxMint, Raspbian), Solaris, OneFS, Data OnTap

Software: KVM, VirtualBox, VMWare, JBoss, Tomcat, WebLogic, Apache, nginx, PostgreSQL, Raidcom, SymCLI, Netapp WFA, Veritas Clustering, LVM, MDAdm, MKS, Git, SVN, Docker, Puppet, Cobbler, OpenLDAP, RStudio

Programming Languages: Bash, Perl, Python, C, LISP

Other: Amazon Web Services (EC2, VPC, S3, RDS), Microsoft HPC cluster, Dell/EMC Isilon; Hitachi SAN frames; Netapp (7-Mode and cDOT) NAS, HPE Server hardware

Professional Experience

Excelsior College UNIX System Engineer

November 2018 – Current

- Worked to bring two orphaned applications up to date and under regular maintenance
- Commissioned new hardware with firmware patches and initial OS installations and software loads
- Participated in planning and design of a customer-facing chatbot
- 100% on-call.

Integratouch, Inc.

October 2017 – November 2018

Release Management Engineer (on contract to SiriusXM)

- Deploy in-house applications to multiple TIBCO Businessworks environments running on RedHat Linux.
- Troubleshoot issues as they arise.
- Liaise with Development and Project Management teams as needed.

9002 Page 1 of 4

- Develop processes and documentation to improve quality and consistency of deployments.
- 100% Telecommuting, 20% on-call.

Logic Technology Inc. July 2016-September 2017 Infrastructure Support Consultant (on contract to General Electric)

- Plan and perform allocation and de-allocation of disk on SAN frames and NAS clusters, including growth, shrinkage, and creation or removal of filesystems on the associated servers .
- Guide the customer through the design process for new storage requests.
- Analyze and remediate performance and reliability concerns with data storage systems.
- Act as liaison to storage vendors to schedule and coordinate hardware repair and maintenance tasks.
- Document technical procedures for repeatability and training.
- Perform exhaustive monthly backup audit to ensure all data is properly protected.
- Train, mentor and advise other team members as needed.
- 20% Telecommuting.

New York Independent System Operator Platform System Administrator

Nov 2007-June 2016

- Deployed and administered JBoss applications on over 900 JBoss servers.
- Maintained NYISO Public Key Infrastructure (PKI) and internal Certificate Authority (CA).
- Wrote NYISO's standard style guide for Perl programs.
- Designed, proved and implemented new standards for deployment of Apache servers within the organization
- Participated in design and deployment of updated NYISO website
- Performed triage and mitigation of Shell Shock and Heartbleed vulnerabilities
- Wrote scripting to start, stop and restart complex and problematic COTS applications, including status monitoring and automatically-forced stops as needed
- Responded to security incidents
- Administered multiple messaging technologies (Software AG WebMethods, TIBCO Rendezvous, JMS) including building infrastructure for interoperability between technologies
- Gathered requirements for moving a department off of legacy shadow-IT reporting system and onto newer, enterprise-grade, standardized technologies.
- Performed software deployment to High Performance Compute (HPC) cluster as needed
- 50% On-call

New York Independent System Operator System Analyst

May 2000-Oct 2007

- Created scheduling system to improve uptime of a critical, but delicate SAS application (scheduler written in Perl)
- Developed PostgreSQL schemas and Perl applications to generate market reports for the Market Analysts
- Process automation using both Control-M and scripted solutions
- Created load pocket monitoring system believed impossible, enabling a short-term remedy for the 2003 blackout

9002 Page 2 of 4

MySudo, Inc DevOps Engineer (concurrent with NYISO)

August 2012-May 2014

- Linux system administration on Ubuntu Linux
- Operating system security hardening
- Internal system patching of Linux, Java, Tomcat, nginx, Rabbit MQ.
- PostgreSQL Database administration, configuration, benchmarking and optimization
- Researched, designed and deployed clustering solutions for high availability and load balancing
- Developed Amazon EC2/VPC based network architecture
- Deployed Squid proxy to provide Internet while maintaining separation for security
- Set up VPN for access to corporate servers from remote locations
- Actively participated in architectural design
- Established procedures for rapid deployment of messaging servers (using Rabbit MQ)
- 100% Telecommuting

Data Tech Associates, Ltd. Senior Engineer

August 1998-May 2000

- Field technical support, including Y2K mitigations.
- After October 1999, on contract to NYISO.

IFS International, Inc. System Support Technician

February 1997-July 1998

• Staged, administered and installed ATM back-end servers and associated networking and cryptographic security.

Tailwind Associates

January 1996-February 1997

Technical Support Engineer (on contract to General Electric)

• Provided telephone and field technical support for GE FANUC software.

Norrell Services

August 1995-December 1995

Network Consultant (on contract to New York State)

 $\bullet \ \ Provided \ NOC \ and \ field \ support \ for \ NY \ State \ Office \ of \ Mental \ Retardation \ and \ Developmental \ Disabilities \ (OMRDD).$

Education/Certifications

College/University

- SUNY Brockport, BS in Computer Science, 1994
- SUNY Alfred, AS in Computer Science, 1991

9002 Page 3 of 4

Other Affiliations/Accomplishments

- In Toastmasters International, served as Sergeant At Arms, Secretary and President. Achieved Advanced Communicator Bronze and Competent Leader designations. Earned first or second place in various speaking competitions.
- General class Amateur Radio Operator.
- Some fluency in French.

9002 Page 4 of 4